Contact

pamonique@msn.com

www.linkedin.com/in/passion-mitchell-6207aa57 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Hospitals Clinical Research Medicine

Passion Mitchell

Registered Nurse at Medix™

Houston

Summary

Experienced Registered Nurse with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Management, Medicine, Working with Physicians, IV Therapy, and Nursing. Strong healthcare services professional with a Bachelor of Science (BS) in nursing focused in Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse from Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center.

Experience

Medix[™]
Registered Nurse
September 2019 - Present (1 year)

Methodist Hospital -Medical Center -Neuromuscular Clinic, Movement Disorders Clinic and Dr. Stanley Appel ALS Clinic

- · Effectively coordinated with physicians and team members regarding changes in patient status, symptomatology, results of diagnostic tests and critical test values.
- · Established effective communication with patient and family members to implement plan of care to ensure coordination of activities and ongoing communication of the patient health status.
- · Facilitated continuity of care for patients including medication refills, lab and other external diagnostic results, assist patient/provider in completing forms.
- · Telephone phone triage for a heavy load of neuromuscular patients with such diagnosis as Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), Myasthenia Gravis, Inflammatory myopathy, Peripheral neuropathy/CIDP, Neuropathy and Neuromuscular disorders.
- · Assisted with patient care in scheduling and placing orders for PEG placements, IVIG infusion, plasmapheresis and multidisciplinary orders.
- · Assisted with prior authorization requests, provided accurate and complete documentation with rationale used to approve request.

- · Communicating with health insurance companies and pharmacy insurance plans for verifications of patients benefits for medications and services.
- · Assist with the Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis grading for patient's progression. Assessing the measure of the subjective health status in the ALS/MND patients.
- · Assess both impairment and disabilities: physical mobility, activities of daily life, eating and drinking abilities, communication and emotional functioning. Utilizing a series of physical assessment testing.

TrialCard

Nurse Educator Field September 2018 - Present (2 years)

- One on one training and education to the patient/family members in understanding and implementing therapy prescribed by the physician. (Omnitrope, Glatopa, Zarxio and Ziextenzo)
- Identify and report any adverse events, medical inquiries, or product complaints per TrialCard and manufacturer guidance. Injection training for patients diagnosed with growth deficiencies, multiple sclerosis & rheumatoid arthritis
- Advise on administration self-injection techniques, area/site rotation, proper storage, handling, and preparation of the medication, dosing and constitution and timelines
- Educate patients on medication side effects
- Utilize motivational interviewing to increase adherence to prescribed treatment plan.
- Complete manufacturer post-visit documentation paperwork and transmit to Clinical Operations
- Administer first aid/CPR or coordinate emergency care (911) as needed
- Identify and report any adverse events, medical inquiries, or product complaints per protocol.
- Maintain accurate travel time and mileage documentation for Concur billing purposes

Pulse Staffing
Registered Nurse
August 2017 - Present (3 years 1 month)
Baylor College of Medicine-Urology Department
June 2019-August 2019

- Educate and support Urology patients daily with care in clinic (IM injections, surgical site care, assist with insertion and discontinuation of urethra Foley for male and female patients.
- Educate, support and encourage patients regarding their prescribed treatment plan.
- Administer intravesical chemotherapy drugs (Mitomycin, Gemcitabine, Docetaxel), immunotherapy drug BCG (Bacillus Calmette-Guerin) and BCG Toyko stand alone to numerous of patients daily.
- Assist with desktop assignment of patient care incoming and follow up care.

Baylor College of Medicine -Geriatrics

August 2018-January 2019

- Educate and support geriatrics patients / average 100 + calls weekly
- Telephone phone triage for geriatric patients with diagnosis such as CHF, HTN, DM, Hyperlipidemia, Metabolic Syndrome, PVD, COPD, Dementia
- Implement critical thinking to provide telephonic guidance & support assigned patient population
- Identify emergent situations with appropriate provider follow-up
- Educate, support and encourage patients regarding prescribed treatment plan
- Provide ongoing education & support for patients and their family members
- Provide support for healthcare providers & fellow team members
- Accurately utilize EPIC EMR system, to communicate with providers & staff with appropriate follow-up

Baylor College of Medicine –Breast Center

April 2018-June 2018

- Assess patients by actively listening via telephone & Identify emergent situations with appropriate provider follow-up.
- Support team mates with in office patient visits
- Administer intramuscular and subcutaneous injections as needed as well as teaching patients
- Accurately utilize EPIC EMR system, to communicate with providers & staff with appropriate follow-up
- Provide support for healthcare providers & fellow team members

MD Anderson Cancer Center Clinical Research Nurse-Investigational Cancer Therapeutics May 2016 - October 2016 (6 months)

- Coordinate activities related to initiation and conduct of clinical trials.
 Appropriate consent forms completed with patients and family members.
 Screen patients for protocol eligibility through personal interviews and /or medical record review.
- Participate in protocol-specific task as needed: Provided nursing assessment and assists in management of toxicities and/or adverse events that patients may experience while on department clinical trials.
- Assist the primary investigator in collection and evaluation of data: Evaluated response to treatment, treatment toxicities and adverse drug reactions and reports appropriately to the principal investigator, the Institutional Review Board and the study sponsor.
- Provide professional and ancillary staff education concerning protocols by written and or computerized directions.
- Coordinated and maintained accurate and current protocol databases as assigned. : Assist with protocol data entry in EPIC system and data analysis.
- Collaborated with Doctor's and staff throughout the patient's care plan.
 Advised of the any emergent situations that may have arise.
- Assessed protocol for patient's to determine if they meet protocol eligibility criteria by: verbally questioning one-on-one, visually reviewing medical records, and evaluating lab, imaging, and other diagnostic tests.

Baylor College of Medicine Registered Nurse Gastroenterology October 2013 - May 2016 (2 years 8 months) Houston, Texas Area

- Educate and support chronic disease patients / average 150 calls weekly for 13 medical providers
- Telephone phone triage for gastro patients with diagnosis such as CD, UC, IBS
- Implement critical thinking to provide telephonic guidance & support to randomly assigned patient population
- Assess patients by actively listening via telephone & Identify emergent situations with appropriate provider follow-up
- Maintain / rotate & re-order medication samples for patients ongoing
- Educate, support and encourage patients regarding prescribed treatment plan
- Teach protocol for test preparations-including colonoscopy, virtual capsule & gastro surgical interventions

- Collaborate with Specialty Pharmacies to obtain prior auths; refills for biologic & other meds utilizing departmental protocol
- Counsel patients on new drugs, diagnoses, labs results, surgical reports & provider recommendations
- Effectively communicate provider prescribed healthcare regimen to patients & families
- Support team mates with in office patient visits
- Administer intramuscular and subcutaneous biologics injections and teaching for CD & UC patients
- Assist physicians with in office surgical procedures / hemorrhoid banding, infrared hemorrhoid treatments
- · Conduct virtual capsule procedures stand alone
- Collaborate with team members to ensure that the clinical day runs smoothly
- Accurately utilize EPIC EMR system, to communicate with providers & staff with appropriate follow-up
- Proficient in iPad technology, Microsoft Word, Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint & EMR Documentation

Park Plaza Hospital Houston, Texas

Park Plaza Hospital-Senior Care Clinic - Triage Nurse/Clinic Nurse October 2012 - October 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Houston, Texas Area

- Assess & care for ambulatory geri patients with CHF, HTN, DM, Hyperlipidemia, Metabolic Syndrome, PVD, COPD, Dementia
- Assess BP, edema-CHF, DM-blood sugar monitoring, cholesterol testing, flu vaccines
- Educate patients on disease state & current treatment plan; w the goal of changing current trajectory & hospital readmissions
- Calm, reassure, support & re-orient dementia patient population to current environment
- Actively listen & provide supportive guidance to patients based upon their healthcare concerns
- Administered injections & other medical treatments as ordered; assess for effectiveness & side effects
- Administer ordered pain medications with follow-up assessment using the Wong-Baker Assessment Tool
- Provide ongoing education & support for patients and their family members
- Provide support for healthcare providers & fellow team members

Holly Hall Retirement Community

NursingHolly Hall Retirement Center Skilled Nursing Floor Nurse

October 2009 - October 2012 (3 years 1 month)

- Supervise nursing team members
- Patient & family teaching / orientation to facility
- Initial assessments for newly admitted patients with appropriate communication to healthcare providers
- Provide care- for pts with chronic diagnosis- CHF, HTN, DM, PVD, Metabolic Syndrome, Hyperlipidemia, COPD
- Employee health nurse-TB skin test administration & assessment for new hires w appropriate communication to HR
- Discharge and transfers of residents to appropriate level of care
- Educate patient's & their family members on plan of care & assess an ongoing understanding
- Administer meds, including pain medications with follow-up assessment using the Wong-Baker Pain Assessment Tool
- Collaborate with healthcare providers, and communicate changes in patient's status with appropriate follow-up
- Educate residents & their family members of any noted condition changes
- Work with healthcare team to monitor charts to ensure accuracy and timely evaluations for assigned residents

Memorial Recruiting, Inc

Nursing

August 2009 - October 2009 (3 months)

Cardiology Office: Answered phone calls from patients concerning their treatment, worked in different databases, filed necessary paper work, followed out doctors orders, phoned patients, gave their labs results and orders given by the doctors.

Berry Healthcare Agency

Nursing

August 2009 - October 2009 (3 months)

Hospice- Provide continuous nursing care to hospice clients ensuring quality nursing care delivery and inform family members of the progress of the client. Health clinic- Perform blood pressure, weight, and height measure measurements. Administer cholesterol testing and flu vaccines as well as providing nursing care.

The Colonnades of the Reflection Bay

Skilled Nursing Floor Nurse

November 2008 - July 2009 (9 months)

Pearland.Texas

- . Supervision of certified nursing assistants
- Educate patients & their families on discharge planning & current plan of care-assess on ongoing understanding
- Orient and train new nursing staff members
- Monitor patients healthcare status & notify physician of changes as appropriate
- Collaborate with team members to provide exceptional patient care
- Assess, administer & monitor medications for chronic conditions such as HTN, PVD, CHF, COPD, Metabolic Syndrome, DM
- Administer meds, including pain medications with follow-up assessment using the 0-10 Pain Assessment Tool
- Assist in admission process for new residents
- Provide ongoing support & assist fellow team members as needed

Belmont Village

Nursing

October 2008 - February 2009 (5 months)

Administers daily medications for the heavy quantity patients and observe for adverse reactions. Perform daily assessments including vitals. Responsible for immediate care of the patient's ex. falls or cuts. Maintain medications cart per shift: reordering patient's medication. Administered TB skin test to new employees when needed and provided assistant to the team when needed.#.

Baylor College of Medicine

7 years 2 months

Tissue Bank Coordinator

August 2004 - August 2007 (3 years 1 month)

- .• Coordinate tissue samples for BCM tissue bank
- Developed a secondary tissue monitoring log/tool to enhance concise accuracy & to support required guidelines
- Assist in building state-of-the-art clinical database to collect & store obtained tissue specimens
- Maintained ongoing database and obtained tissue samples from participating hospitals
- Utilized vast knowledge of dry ice while appropriately packing tissue samples utilizing strict departmental guidelines

- Managed 40 degree upright freezer / catalogued & maintained various tissue samples, utilizing strict protocol
- Communicate / collaborate with clients to verify ability to obtain tissues samples
- Collaborated with Institutional Review Board
- Obtained patient consent forms
- Provide ongoing communication with fellow team members
- Educate staff on changes in outlined protocol
- Maintain standards of excellence

Administrative Secretary

July 2000 - August 2004 (4 years 2 months)

Provided assistance to Pathologist and Pathologist Assistant in their daily duties: This included answering phone calls, managed office daily duties. Helped Pathologist in getting their articles published by researching many diseases, maintained photos database for the department of Pathology, and obtain specimens for the department of Pathology.

Auxiliary Home Health, Inc Certified Nurses Aide

November 1999 - July 2000 (9 months)

Provided direct patient care in establishments in Hospice and Nursing homes: emphasis place on meeting both physical and emotional needs of residents.

Education

Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center
Bachelor of Science (BS) in nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2014 - 2014)

Lamar State College-Port Arthur
Associate's degree in Nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2012 - 2013)

Houston Community College
Graduate Vocational Nurse · (2007 - 2008)

Houston Community College

Associate Degree, Arts · (2003)